Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine.
我是Catherine。
And we're in the mood to read something today, so we're going to a place called the library,
今天我们心情不错，想读点东西，所以我们要去一个叫图书馆的地方。
right?
对吧？
That's right.
没错。
We're going to go to the library and we're going to get some books.
我们要去图书馆，借几本书。
But before we do that, let's take a look at a word in vocabulary preview.
但在那之前，我们先来看看词汇预览里的一个词。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
All right.
好的。
So, today's vocabulary preview word is a thing that you use when you go to the library to
所以，今天词汇预览的词是你去图书馆时用来把书带回家的东西。
take that book home.
把书带回家。
You don't have to pay for the book.
你不需要为这本书付钱。
You use your library card to borrow it.
你用借书证来借书。
That's right.
没错。
So, this is something that you need when you want to get books at the library.
所以，这是你想在图书馆借书时需要的东西。
You need a library card.
你需要一张借书证。
So, we're going to talk about this and how you get a library card.
那么，我们要聊聊这个，以及如何办一张借书证。
So, let's listen to the dialogue.
现在，我们来听对话。
Wow!
哇！
Look at all these books.
看看这些书。
I bet I can find a book about anything here.
我敢打赌，这里什么书都能找到。
Shh!
嘘！
Please keep your voice down.
请小声点。
There are people reading and studying here.
这里有人在看书和学习。
Okay.
好的。
I'm sorry.
对不起。
Are you the librarian?
你是图书管理员吗？
Maybe you can help me.
也许你能帮我。
I am looking for a book.
我在找一本书。
Yes, I am.
是的，我是。
You can check our online catalog to search for the book you want based on the genre,
你可以查我们的在线目录，根据类型、书名来搜索你想要的书，或者如果你知道作者，我可以给你指路。
title, or if you know the author, I can point you towards the right direction.
或者如果你知道作者，我可以给你指路。
I'm looking for a book that has nursery rhymes.
我在找一本有童谣的书。
That would be in our children's section.
那应该在儿童区。
That bookshelf there on the right.
右边那个书架就是。
Okay.
好的。
I would like to check out these books.
我想借这些书。
Do you have a library card?
你有借书证吗？
No.
没有。
How do I get one?
我怎么办一张？
I just need to see your driver's license or utility bill to prove that you are a resident
我只需要看你的驾照或水电费账单，证明你是本州居民。
of this state.
证明你是本州居民。
Here you go.
给你。
So, you're all set.
好了，你办好了。
You can have these books for two weeks.
这些书你可以借两周。
If you need to have them longer, you can bring them here to renew them.
如果你需要借更久，可以带回来续借。
If you don't, you get charged 10 cents a day for each book.
如果不续借，每本书每天要收10美分。
Okay.
好的。
Thanks.
谢谢。
All right.
好了。
We're back.
我们回来了。
So, now, let's start with Language Takeaway.
那么，现在开始语言要点。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
All right.
好的。
We have a lot of great things for you today in Language Takeaway.
今天语言要点里有很多好东西。
The first is actually a job.
第一个其实是一个职业。
This is a person who works at a library.
这是在图书馆工作的人。
What's that person called?
那个人叫什么？
He or she is called a librarian.
他或她叫图书管理员。
All right.
好的。
So, someone who works at a library is a librarian.
所以，在图书馆工作的人就是图书管理员。
That's right.
没错。
So, this person organizes the books, knows about all the books that are there, and basically
这个人整理书籍，了解所有书的内容，基本上负责管理图书馆。
takes care of the library.
负责管理图书馆。
That's right.
没错。
So, if you need help in the library, it's probably a good idea to ask the librarian
所以，如果你在图书馆需要帮助，最好问图书管理员你要找的书在哪里。
where the book you're looking for is.
你要找的书在哪里。
That's right.
没错。
And today, we went in looking for a specific type of book.
今天，我们去找了一本特定类型的书。
We wanted a book that had nursery rhymes.
我们想要一本有童谣的书。
All right.
好的。
Nursery rhymes.
童谣。
Now, these are kind of like songs or poems, things that we tell little children and babies.
这些有点像歌曲或诗歌，是我们讲给小孩和婴儿听的。
So, Mary had a little lamb, little lamb.
比如“玛丽有只小羊羔，小羊羔”。
That is a nursery rhyme.
那就是一首童谣。
It's a playful poem for children.
这是给孩子们的有趣诗歌。
That's right.
没错。
So, obviously, since we are looking for nursery rhyme books, the librarian told us that we
所以，显然，因为我们在找童谣书，图书管理员告诉我们得去儿童区。
need to go to the children's section.
得去儿童区。
That's right.
没错。
Now, before we get to borrow this book, there are a couple of things we need because the
现在，在我们借这本书之前，有几件事需要处理，因为
person doesn't have a library card.
那个人没有借书证。
Now, the question is, how do I get a library card?
问题是，我怎么才能拿到借书证？
What was the librarian's response, Marco?
图书管理员是怎么回答的，Marco？
Well, it was pretty simple.
嗯，很简单。
All we needed was to see that person's driver's license or a utility bill.
我们只需要看那个人的驾照或水电账单。
All right.
好的。
So, a driver's license is an ID card, an identification card that you get that allows
所以，驾照是一种身份证件，是你获得的一种允许
you to drive a car.
你开车的证件。
Now, each state has a different kind of driver's license and different rules for how to get
每个州都有不同类型的驾照和不同的获取规则，
one, but this is a very common, almost the most common kind of identification in America.
但这在美国是非常常见、几乎是最常见的身份证明方式。
That's right.
没错。
So, basically, you show them your driver's license and it has a picture of you there,
基本上，你给他们看你的驾照，上面有你的照片、
your telephone number, and even your address.
电话号码，甚至还有你的地址。
That's right.
没错。
But not everybody has a driver's license.
但并不是每个人都有驾照。
Some people don't drive.
有些人不开车。
Some people can't drive.
有些人不能开车。
Some people don't want to drive.
有些人不想开车。
So, they would have to show something else.
所以，他们得出示其他东西。
And a good way to show that you live somewhere is to show your utility bill.
而证明你住在某处的一个好方法就是出示你的水电账单。
That's right.
没错。
So, a utility is basically water, electricity, gas, or your telephone bill, and it arrives
所以，公用事业基本上就是水、电、煤气或电话账单，它会寄到
to your house and that's where it's, well, obviously, it says your address there and
你家，上面显然有你的地址和
who the bill is directed to.
账单的收件人。
So, you can prove that you live there.
这样你就能证明你住在那里。
That's right.
没错。
Because why would somebody else pay for the water at that house?
因为别人为什么要为那栋房子的水费买单呢？
It's obviously you.
显然是你。
So, these are a couple kinds of identification you can use to get a library card.
所以，这些是你可以用来办理借书证的几种身份证明。
All right.
好的。
And while we're taking the books, we can borrow them for two weeks, but if we need to have
而且我们借书时，可以借两周，但如果需要
them for a longer period of time, we can take them back to the library and have them renewed.
更长时间，我们可以把书带回图书馆续借。
So, to renew something, renew, means to continue to borrow it.
所以，续借某物，renew，意思是继续借阅。
You have to re-borrow.
你得重新借。
But we don't say re-borrow.
但我们不说 re-borrow。
We say renew.
我们说 renew。
So, that means we get it for another two weeks.
这意味着我们可以再借两周。
That's right.
没错。
So, things that expire, usually you need to renew, like for example, your driver's license.
所以，会过期的东西通常需要续期，比如你的驾照。
Usually it will last maybe five years, but then you need to renew your driver's license.
通常有效期是五年，但之后你需要续期驾照。
And if you don't renew it, if you forget to renew something, maybe there'll be a problem.
如果你不续期，如果你忘了续期某物，可能会有麻烦。
Like in the case of the library, you have to pay for the late fees.
比如在图书馆，你得付逾期费。
Your book is overdue.
你的书过期了。
You have to pay for it.
你得付钱。
Or in the case of a driver's license, if your driver's license is overdue, well, you probably
或者拿驾照来说，如果你的驾照过期了，那你可能
have to get a new one.
得办一张新的。
That's right.
没错。
Okay, so a lot of vocab there.
好的，这里有很多词汇。
Why don't we review everything and we'll be right back.
我们不如复习一下所有内容，马上回来。
Wow!
哇！
Look at all these books!
看看这些书！
I bet I can find a book about anything here!
我敢打赌这里什么书都能找到！
Shh!
嘘！
Please keep your voice down.
请小声点。
There are people reading and studying here.
这里有人在阅读和学习。
Okay, I'm sorry.
好的，对不起。
Are you the librarian?
你是图书管理员吗？
Maybe you can help me.
也许你能帮我。
I am looking for a book.
我在找一本书。
Yes, I am.
是的，我是。
You can check our online catalog to search for the book you want based on the genre,
你可以查我们的在线目录，根据类型、
title, or if you know the author, I can point you towards the right direction.
书名搜索你要的书，或者如果你知道作者，我可以给你指路。
I'm looking for a book that has nursery rhymes.
我在找一本有童谣的书。
That would be in our children's section.
那在我们的儿童区。
That bookshelf there on the right.
右边那个书架。
Okay, I would like to check out these books.
好的，我想借这些书。
Do you have a library card?
你有借书证吗？
No, how do I get one?
没有，我怎么才能办一个？
I just need to see your driver's license or utility bill to prove that you are a resident
我只需要看你的驾照或水电账单，证明你是本州
of this state.
居民。
Here you go.
给你。
So you're all set.
所以你都办好了。
You can have these books for two weeks.
这些书你可以借两周。
If you need to have them longer, you can bring them here to renew them.
如果你需要更长时间，可以带回来续借。
If you don't, you get charged 10 cents a day for each book.
如果不续借，每本书每天收费10美分。
Okay, thanks.
好的，谢谢。
Alright, so now we have three key phrases for you on Fluency Builder.
好了，现在我们在流利度构建器中有三个关键短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
So Marco, what are librarians famous for?
那么，马可，图书馆员以什么闻名？
Well, librarians are always telling you to please keep your voice down.
嗯，图书馆员总是告诉你请小声说话。
Alright, so libraries are quiet places.
好吧，所以图书馆是安静的地方。
They're places where people like to go and read and think and study.
它们是人们喜欢去阅读、思考和学习的场所。
So oftentimes when people are talking, they're being loud, the librarian will say, hey, keep
所以很多时候，当人们在说话、声音很大时，图书馆员会说，嘿，请
your voice down or be quiet.
小声点或安静。
That's right.
没错。
So another way of saying be quiet is keep your voice down.
所以“安静”的另一种说法是“小声点”。
And it's a little bit more polite.
而且这稍微礼貌一些。
Please keep your voice down.
请小声点。
Keep your voice down.
小声点。
Or if there's two people or three people, you'd say, keep your voices down.
或者如果有两个人或三个人，你会说，请你们小声点。
So the librarian tells us to keep our voice down.
所以图书馆员告诉我们小声点。
And well, now we can get some help from the librarian.
嗯，现在我们可以从图书馆员那里得到一些帮助。
And he says that, you know, if you know the title of the book or the genre or the name
他说，你知道，如果你知道书名、类型或作者的名字，
of the author, the librarian can point you towards the right direction.
图书馆员可以为你指明正确的方向。
Now to point someone in the right direction or point someone towards the right direction
现在，“为某人指明正确的方向”或“指引某人朝正确的方向”
means to help them understand where to go.
意思是帮助他们理解该去哪里。
Maybe they don't know exactly the title of the book or the author, but in this case,
也许他们不知道确切的书名或作者，但在这个情况下，
the librarian can help put the person in the right place.
图书馆员可以帮助把这个人放到正确的位置。
So I can point you in the right direction or point you towards the right direction.
所以我可以为你指明正确的方向，或者指引你朝正确的方向。
Exactly.
正是如此。
Even maybe you're lost in a town and you stop and ask someone for directions because you
甚至可能你在一个城镇里迷路了，你停下来问路，因为你
don't know how to get there.
不知道怎么去那里。
And that person can help you by pointing you towards the right direction.
那个人可以通过为你指明正确的方向来帮助你。
All right.
好的。
So this means I can help you basically.
所以这基本上意味着我可以帮助你。
Okay.
好的。
And now what we wanted to do was we wanted to borrow books from the library.
现在我们想做的是从图书馆借书。
We wanted to get books from the library.
我们想从图书馆拿书。
But we have another way of saying this.
但我们有另一种说法。
We can say we want to check out some books.
我们可以说我们想借出一些书。
All right.
好的。
So to check out a book means to borrow it, like you say.
所以“借出”一本书意味着借它，就像你说的。
But this is also a noun.
但这也是一个名词。
Check out.
借出柜台。
That's the place where you scan something.
那是你扫描东西的地方。
So maybe there's a bar, a black bar on the back of the book.
所以也许书背面有一个条形码，一个黑色条码。
When you scan it, it scans out.
当你扫描它时，它就扫描出去了。
That means that you're borrowing it.
这意味着你在借它。
You get it for two weeks and you bring it back to check out.
你可以借两周，然后带回来还书。
Okay.
好的。
So a lot of great stuff in this dialogue today, learning about libraries and how to get a
所以今天的对话里有很多好东西，学习关于图书馆以及如何办
library card.
借书证。
Why don't we review everything one last time?
我们最后再复习一遍好吗？
Wow!
哇！
Look at all these books.
看看所有这些书。
I bet I can find a book about anything here.
我打赌我在这里能找到关于任何东西的书。
Shh!
嘘！
Please keep your voice down.
请小声点。
There are people reading and studying here.
这里有人在阅读和学习。
Okay.
好的。
I'm sorry.
对不起。
Are you the librarian?
你是图书馆员吗？
Maybe you can help me.
也许你能帮我。
I am looking for a book.
我在找一本书。
Yes, I am.
是的，我是。
You can check our online catalog to search for the book you want based on the genre,
你可以查我们的在线目录，根据类型、书名搜索你想要的书，或者如果你知道作者，
title, or if you know the author, I can point you towards the right direction.
我可以为你指明正确的方向。
I'm looking for a book that has nursery rhymes.
我在找一本有童谣的书。
That would be in our children's section.
那会在我们的儿童区。
That bookshelf there on the right.
右边那个书架。
Okay I would like to check out these books.
好的，我想借出这些书。
Do you have a library card?
你有借书证吗？
No.
没有。
How do I get one?
我怎么办一张？
I just need to see your driver's license or utility bill to prove that you are a resident
我只需要看你的驾照或水电费账单，以证明你是这个州的
of this state.
居民。
Here you go.
给你。
So you're all set.
所以你都办好了。
You can have these books for two weeks.
这些书你可以借两周。
If you need to have them longer, you can bring them here to renew them.
如果你需要借更长时间，你可以带它们来这里续借。
If you don't, you get charged 10 cents a day for each book.
如果不续借，每本书每天会收10美分的费用。
Okay, thanks.
好的，谢谢。
All right.
好的。
So borrowing books in a library seems pretty simple and you don't really have to leave
所以在图书馆借书看起来很简单，你不需要真的留下
a deposit or something just in case you steal the book or you damage it.
押金之类的东西，以防你偷书或损坏它。
How do you deal with this?
你们怎么处理这个？
No, well libraries are a wonderful part of, well at least American culture.
不，嗯，图书馆是，至少美国文化中很美好的一部分。
I'm not really sure how they work in other places, but in America there's a lot of federal
我不太确定其他地方怎么运作，但在美国有很多联邦
money in libraries.
图书馆里的钱。
In fact, I think it was Franklin Roosevelt who really helped get a library system in
事实上，我认为是富兰克林·罗斯福真正帮助建立了图书馆系统。
place in America.
在美国的一个地方。
So they're a part of this system of kind of community sharing and information.
所以他们也是这种社区共享和信息体系的一部分。
You can go to the library and look for jobs.
你可以去图书馆找找工作。
They have computers.
他们有电脑。
Many have DVD and video sections.
许多都有DVD和视频专区。
Many have very wonderful CD sections.
很多都有非常棒的CD区。
So basically it's a community center for information, knowledge.
所以基本上，它是一个信息与知识的社区中心。
And it's almost a relationship of trust.
这几乎是一种信任关系。
I trust that the library will provide for me and the library will trust that I don't
我相信图书馆会为我提供所需，而图书馆也相信我不会辜负这份信任。
destroy a book.
毁掉一本书。
Of course, if you do, you have to pay.
当然，如果你要这么做，就得付钱。
You have to pay.
你必须付钱。
So is it a federal offense to steal a book from a library?
那么，从图书馆偷书算是联邦犯罪吗？
I don't know, but it's a pretty big deal to steal a book from the library.
我不知道，但从图书馆偷书可是件大事。
They certainly will know who you are because they have your information, your driver's
他们当然会知道你是谁，因为他们有你的信息，你的驾照。
license.
抱歉，您提供的输入似乎不完整。请提供完整的字幕内容（包括 id 和英文文本），以便我按照要求进行翻译。
Right.
好的。
It's actually pretty interesting, especially because, as you said, libraries, there's
这其实挺有意思的，尤其是因为，就像你说的，图书馆，那里有
a lot of money put into libraries.
投入了大量资金在图书馆上。
So all communities have them, as you say, DVDs or movies or a lot of different types
正如你所说，所有社区都有它们，比如DVD、电影或许多不同类型的作品。
of books.
书的。
And in other countries, like maybe in Latin America, it's not as popular to have a community
在其他国家，比如拉丁美洲，社区文化可能没那么流行。
library where you can go and check things out because there's not that much money involved
图书馆，你可以去那里借东西，因为不需要花太多钱。
as well.
也一样。
But we would be curious to know how it works in your country.
但我们很好奇，在你们国家是怎么运作的。
Maybe your country has some beautiful or extensive libraries.
也许你的国家有一些漂亮或规模宏大的图书馆。
Yeah, I'm very curious as well.
嗯，我也很好奇。
So public libraries, do you have them?
那么公共图书馆，你们那里有吗？
And if you don't, do you also have university libraries you can go to?
如果你没有的话，你们也有大学图书馆可以去吗？
Let us know.
告诉我们。
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是EnglishPod.com。
All right, guys, we'll see you there.
好了，各位，我们到时候见。
Bye.
再见。
Bye
再见